

# Donald McLamb

Full-Stack Web Developer & Cyber Security Professional

## Contact Me:



443.677.8501



, mclamb.donald@gmail.com



cyberdesigns.io



http://github.com/dmc2015

## **Primary Skills:**









## Other Technical Skills:

### Management & Other IT Skills

- PostgreSQL
- Foundations
- Github
- AWS
- Heroku
- Microsoft Server 2012

#### Methodologies & Processes

- Agile Design
- Entity Relational Diagram
- MVC
- Wire framing

## Misc. Software

- Image Editing Software
- Bash
- Vim
- Atom

## Overview

A skilled full-stack developer and cybersecurity professional dedicated to the safety and security of information as well as the user experience. Seasoned problem solver with a strong drive to develop useful, secure applications and software that promote solutions to relevant security concerns.

## **Industry Experience and Projects**

Cyberdesigns.io, Gaithersburg MD, June 2015 - Present
A freelance company I started to continue the development of my portfolio.

**VoxPopuli** - <u>voxpopuli-.herokuapp.com</u>, July 2015 - September 2015 A individual MEAN stack, based on a Reddit clone. The application is designed to share information and public opninion among users.

Technologies used: HTML, Mongo, Express, Angular, Node, Gulp, CSS, Bootstrap, Passport

## Formula I Stats - formula-1-stats.herokuapp.com, September 2015

A Angular.js and Node based app using a external API to display Formula-1 race stats. It uses a custom mapping object to keep the app DRY. Future iterations will allow users to pick what year they can see stats on.

Technologies used: HTML, Angular, Node, Bootstrap, CSS, Gulp

DayTrackr - <u>daytrackr.meteor.com</u>, June 2015 - Present A individual project, currently in a prototype state using Meteor.js. It is mobile compatibile and responsive. The end result will be a multi-platform scheduler

Technologies used: Meteor.js, HTML, CSS, Foundations

**General Assembly, Washington DC,** *March 2015 - June 2015*WDI student at a full-stack web development program focused on best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development.

SecurityPulse - securitypulse.herokuapp.com, May 2015 - May 2015 A individual project that was developed to centralizing cyber security information while also providing a resource for people to discuss cybersecurity issues. Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, Pry, ActiveRecord, PostgresSQL, CanCanCan, Devise, HTML, CSS

DC Science Hackathon, Washington DC, March 2015 - March 2015 A 2-day event to develop something creative and impactful while collaborating.

PoliConnect - policonnect.org, March 2015 - July 2015

A group project for a DC Science Hackathon, the app's function is to connect policy makers to experts anonymously so that productive debates can take place.

Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, PostgresSQL, CanCanCan, FFaker, AWS, Strategiezed Security Solutions

## **Employment History**

and alarm app.

#### Axxis Software, Gaithersburg MD, May 2013 - April 2015

Software Support Engineer

- Supported customers, IT staff and performed server migrations
- Reviewed and analyzed system logs to find environmental issues
- Advised on security practices, server configuration

#### Motionsoft, Rockville MD, April 2012 - May 2013

Software Support Engineer

- Implemented and trained customers on CMS systems
- Troubleshooted hand key scanners, control access systems
- Executed SQL queries to troubleshoot issues

## Education

**Codementors - Online,** June 2015 - August 2015 Angular JS Online Course

**General Assembly - Washington DC**, March 2015 - June 2015 Web Development Immersive Course

**UMUC - Adelphi MD**, September 2011 - December 2014 Masters of Science - Cybersecurity

**Towson University - Towson MD**, September 2006 - December 2010 Bachelors of Science - Sociology & Psychology